Finding Aid for Michigan Woman's Christian Temperance Union records, 1874-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Local Union Records
  - North Adams
    - Minute book, 1936-1949 (Box 17)
  - Otsego Minute Book, 1942-1952 (Box 13)
  - Owosso
    - Minute Books, 1874-1955; 3 volumes (Box 13)
    - Minutes, 1961-1992; 3 folders; 1 volumes (Box 13)
  - Petoskey Secretary's Book, 1908-1909 (Box 13)
  - Pickford Union, 1958-1964 (Box 13)
  - Pontiac
    - Clippings and Songs, 1898-1942 (Box 14)
    - Histories, circa 1940s (Box 14)
    - Minutes, 1910-1925; 6 volumes (Box 14)
    - Notes, circa 1918-1920 (Box 14)
    - Secretary's Books, 1925-1941; 4 volumes (Box 14)
  - Pontiac-Anna Gordon Union Secretary's Books, 1921-1973; 6 volumes (Box 14)
  - Pontiac-Mary Morton Union Minute Books, 1956-1969; 2 volumes (Box 14)
  - Portage Minutes, 1962-1976 (Box 14)
  - Redford
    - Minutes, 1969-1980 (Box 15)
    - Scrapbook (in 1 folder), 1954-1970 (Box 15)
    - Secretary's Book, 1956-1969 (Box 15)
  - St. Louis Minutes, 1958-1986; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Swartz Creek
    - Membership Book, 1944-1945 (Box 15)
    - Minutes, 1964-1980; 2 volumes; 1 folders (Box 15)
    - Secretary's Books, 1909-1919; 1936-1941; 2 volumes (Box 15)
  - Vassar Secretary's Books, 1889-1895; 1965-1969; 2 volumes (Box 15)
  - Willard Minute Book, 1928-1929 (Box 15)
  - Williamston Secretary's Books, 1949-1969; 3 volumes (Box 15)
  - Woodland Secretary's Books, 1930-1948; 2 volumes (Box 15)
- Photographs
  Photographs (0.1; ca.1900-1960s) contains portraits of WCTU leaders, including Anna Gordon and Lucy Bliss, as well as group pictures taken at the state conventions of 1908 and 1917.
  - Photographs, circa 1900-1960s (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous: include portrait of Anna Gordon, undated, and group portraits of delegates to state conventions, 1908; 1917 (Box 15)
Related Material
The library has separately cataloged published materials of the Michigan Woman's Christian Temperance Union. These include newsletters, annual reports, and minutes and reports of the annual convention. The library also has records from individual local chapters, including Ann Arbor, Battle Creek, Evart, the Flint Federation, Three Oaks, and Ypsilanti.